Bruce Gansner

West Chester, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Bruce-Gansner/b24db30db455976d

Senior Process Control Engineer with extensive DCS and PLC experience in petroleum refining. Have implemented projects using Invensys IA and Honeywell TDC 3000 DCS. Have designed and installed PLC systems including Modicon, Siemens, Rockwell(Allen-Bradley) and HIMA. Have designed and implemented safety systems using SIL technology. Have designed PI, Wonderware, and various other HMI systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Process Control Engineer

ConocoPhillips - Trainer, PA - 1997 to Present

Senior Process Control System Engineer Responsible for the development and implementation of controls on Invensys IA, Honeywell TDC 3000, and Wonderware systems. Implemented over 30 SIS systems and various other PLC applications for alarming and control.

- * Replaced single loop controllers with Invensys IA DCS
- * Developed controls and safety systems for two new Boilers per NFPA 85
- * Developed controls and safety systems for process units involved in EPA Clean Fuels
- * Led alarm rationalization effort for the entire south side of the refinery
- * Developed the PI information system for the entire refinery
- * Supported the CEMS monitoring system both in maintenance and engineering
- * Installed and managed PI system

Senior Insrument Engineer

Sun Oil Co - Marcus Hook, PA - 1996 to 1996

1996

Senior Instrument Engineer Responsible for the development and implementation of primarily analytical controls for the entire complan

- * Commissioned ethylene oxide analyzer at Marcus Hook refinery
- * Developed CEMS monitoring for boilers at ethylene unit Marcus Hook refinery
- * Designed cumene analyzer for Philadelphia refinery
- * Designed and replaced slide valve controls during turnaround Marcus Hook refinery

Control Systems Engineer

BP Oil Co - Marcus Hook, PA - 1994 to 1996

Control System Engineer Responsible for the development and implementation of controls on Foxboro SPEC 200 single loop controllers, the Honeywell TDC 2000 system, and the information system

- * Designed and commissioned Benzene Reduction Facility
- * Designed and installed 7 new gas chromatographs
- * Developed management reports to aid in the profitable operation of the refinery
- * Maintained the Fox 1/A process monitoring and control computer
- * Installed and maintained advanced regulatory controls on the hydrocracker and reformer

Control Systems Engineer

BP Oil Co - Cleveland, OH - 1990 to 1994

Control System Engineer Responsible for the development and implementation of controls and information systems at 5 BP refineries

- * Designed and commissioned Setcon information system Marcus Hook and Ferndale refineries
- * Developed document management standards in joint venture with Amoco and Chevron
- * Reviewed various process scenarios for bottoms upgrade Marcus Hook refinery
- * Designed and commissioned DMC control on Toledo refinery FCC

Refinery Operations Manager

BP Oil Co - Cleveland, OH - 1986 to 1989

Refinery Operations Manager Responsible for the coordination of 5 BP refineries with wholesale marketing, crude and products trading, and corporate planning

- * Eliminated leaded gasoline from all markets
- * Served as emergency operator during labor strike at Marcus Hook refinery
- * Reviewed and validated LP models for all 5 refineries
- * Developed coking opportunities at Toledo refinery

Instrumentation Section Lead

BP Oil Co - Marcus Hook, PA - 1984 to 1986

Instrumentation Section Leader Responsible for the supervision and training of 20 Instrument Technicians.

- * Developed a shift maintenance rotation that better served the refinery
- * Developed and led a training program for technicians

Control Engineer

BP Oil Co - Marcus Hook, PA - 1975 to 1984

Control Engineer Responsible for the safe and continuous operation of the Marcus Hook Refinery

- * Developed and maintained advanced control schemes on Fox 1/A
- * Supported the GCS Setcon interfaces
- * Implemented alarming systems to aid in safe operation

EDUCATION

MBA

Widener University - Chester, PA 1982

Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering

University of Missouri - Rolla, MO 1975

SKILLS

PLC Programming - Siemens, Allen-Bradley(Rockwell), Modicon, and HIMA. DCS Experience with Invensys and TDC 3000. HMI Experience with Wonderware Intouch, Modicon Vijeo, Allen-Bradley RSView, and ProFace.